Inventory of the International Association for the Evaluation of Educational Achievement Records, 1959-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- Miscellaneous IEA materials "not sorted: meetings 1984; meetings 1983; application to join IEA from the Central Institute of Educational Research Beijing China 1984 (Box 475)
- Questionnaires translations (Box 476)
- Science - National documents (Box 476)
- Science (??) (Box 476)
- IEA Council meeting, Budapest Oct 1971 (Box 477)
- Science, sub-test (Box 477)
- Accounting information (Box 477)
- Questionnaires, comments from national centers on Pre-Test Instruments (Box 478)
- NCSQ - children in general (Box 478)
- NCSQ (contd.) (Box 478)
- SIMS (math 2) binders: items, item validation, correspondence etc (Box 179)
- Guessing Study, 1970 (Box 480)
- Guessing Study, 1970-1972 (Box 480)
- Collection of tests (filled with students' names) (Box 481)
- Collection of tests (filled) (Box 482)
- Collection of tests (filled, not in English) (Box 483)
- Collection of tests (filled, not in English) (Box 484)
- Tests, questionnaires and booklets [not in English, different titles maybe its six-subject] (Box 484)
- Replies to IEA/A/1988 1989 1990s, by country (Box 485)
- Materials Husen 1968 (Box 485)
- Collection of tests (Box 486)
- Tests, questionnaires and booklets (Box 486)
- Replies to IEA Documents, 1972/1973, by countries (Box 487)
- Replies to IEA Documents, 1960s - 1970s (Box 487)
- Replies to IEA/A/1988 1989 1990s. Documents are from the 1970s (Box 488)
- Replies to documents, including various A documents (Box 488)
- Replies to IEA A Documents, 1970/1971 (Box 489)
- Replies to IEA A Documents, 1970/1971 (Box 489)
- Replies to IEA Documents, 1971/1972 (Box 490)
- Writing study, test, questionnaires and composition (Box 490)
- IEA Bulletin Phase II Stage 3, French as Foreign Language, Oct 1969 (Box 491)
- Diverse IEA correspondence 1968 (Box 492)
- Results of reading speed and literature, 1968 (Box 493)
- Copies and drafts of Publication on Mathematics, 1968 (Box 493)
- Science collated item analysis (Box 493)
- ESL, National versions in Thailand, Italy and Chile (Box 494)
- IEA math study phase I: case study questionnaire (Box 495)
- Civic Education, pre-tests (Box 495)
- Science collated items and pre-tests (Box 495)
- French as Foreign Language, Six Subject data bank manual (Box 495)
- Stage III, Data ID (??) (Box 496)
- Math Study, Phase I, sampling Japan USA (Box 497)
- Collection of stats documents (Box 498)
- IEA Tokyo meeting, 1978 (Box 499)
- Documents and papers, 1979/1981 (Box 499)
- folders without titles or identifying information (Box 500)
- Coding sheets and lists [seems like French as Foreign Language] (Box 501)
- Coding sheets and lists, 1963-1964 (Box 502)
- Questionnaires (not in English) (Box 503)
- NCSQ from different countries, 1963s (Box 503)
- Collection of reports and publications from 1970s and 1985 (Box 504)
- Coding sheets or scores sheets [not sure for which study or country] (Box 504)
- Six Subject Study instrument, from the Netherlands (Box 505)
- Instruments, school questionnaires and other related materials (Box 506)
- Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 507)
- Miscellaneous, documents and finance (Box 508)
- Collection: materials and documents about the 2nd Math Study, [seems to be early texts], 1970s (Box 509)
- French as Foreign Language, 1968/1969. [Among others there are texts about the rational for the study and background information] (Box 509)
- Collection of materials about the French as Foreign Language, Science and other studies (Box 510)
- Collection of publications, something about Macro-Sociology (Box 510)
- Collection of materials about Six Subject study, NCSQ, national manuals and school questionnaires (Box 511)
- Coding sheets and scores (Box 512)
- Coding sheets, 1971/1974 (Box 513)
- Publications in Swedish (Box 513)
- Collection of papers and presentations on International students and mobility between countries (Box 514)
- Miscellaneous documents (not in English) (Box 514)
- APA style guide (Box 515)
- 1982 by months, International Center for Comparative Education, Sweden (Box 515)
- Folders with test-related materials, questionnaires and more (Box 516)
- Collection of Miscellaneous, budget, finance and related materials (Box 517)
- IEA General Volume, 1974 (Box 518)
- Collection of tests and questionnaires (Box 518)
- Tests from Sweden (Box 519)
- Tests? (Box 520)
- Miscellaneous 1971 (Box 521)
- Miscellaneous 1974 (Box 521)
- Miscellaneous 1970s (Box 521)
- Miscellaneous 1971 (Box 522)
- Miscellaneous 1969 (Box 522)
- Miscellaneous 1973s (Box 522)
- Miscellaneous 1973s (Box 522)
- Miscellaneous 1971s (Box 522)
- Documents, not in English (Box 523)
- Reading Comprehension, 1969 (Box 524)
- Civic Education, interview and pretest, 1967 (Box 524)
- Pre-testing and test booklets - Literature (Box 525)
- Collection of papers about National Case Study Questionnaire, Foreign Language and Civic Education, 1971 (Box 525)
- Box with cards "Country" of contacts or informants in different countries (Box 526)
- Box with cards "IEA Karte I" of contacts, companies (Box 527)
- Tests and questionnaires, English as Foreign language (Box 528)
- Tests and questionnaires, unknown (Box 529)
- Tests and questionnaires, Civics, not English (Box 530)
- Computer printouts, May 1981 (Box 531)
- Computer printouts, May 1981 (Box 532)
- Computer printouts, May 1981 (Box 533)
- Computer printouts, May 1981 [one of them is Math] (Box 534)
- Science, collated items analysis (Box 535)
- Receipts from 1961 (Box 536)
- IEA Bulletin #3, 1964 (Box 537)
- IEA Bulletin #2, 1963 (Box 537)
- IEA Bulletin #4, 1964 (Box 537)
- Data Bank documents 1974-1975 (Box 538)
- IEA Science I, 1967-1968 (Box 538)
- Data Bank correspondence, outside IEA sorted by state (Box 539)
- Data Processing, Coding and Punching, correspondence with national centers (Box 540)
- Six-subject Study Data Bank Manuals, Master Stage 2 and 3 (Box 541)
- Data Analysis, Ideas and Schedule, 1970s (Box 542)
- Data Processing correspondence, 1969/1970 (Box 542)
- Data Bank, Dirty Data File, Stage 2 (Box 543)
- IEA GA meeting, Singapore 1984 (Box 544)
- Miscellaneous, Data Processing Information, Math Data Bank (Box 544)
- Science documents (Box 545)
- Science documents, re test (Box 545)
- Pop 4, Physics, subtests (Box 546)
- Pop 4, Science - Biology (Box 547)
- IEA documents and meetings 1980s (Box 547)
- Publication: Report from Harvard GSE 1961 "An application of reinforcement principles to classroom teaching" (Box 548)
- IEA Harvard conference 1973, papers and more (Box 549)
- IEA Council meeting 1972, travel arrangements and accommodation (Box 550)
- IEA Council meeting, 1972 Frankfurt [copy of Roy Phillips] (Box 551)
- IEA Council meetings binder 1971 (Box 552)
- International Symposium on Evaluation of Educational Achievement, 23-27 Oct 1972 (Box 553)
- IEA Council meeting binder 1971 (Box 554)
- IEA meeting, Tokyo Japan, Jan 23-27, 1978 (Box 555)
- IEA GA meeting, Paris, Sep 1979 (Box 556)
- IEA Symposium and Council meeting, Italy March - April 1977 (Box 557)
- IEA Council meeting 1977, Italy (Box 558)
- IEA Council meeting 1978 (Box 558)
- Originals of Documents and Manuscripts (collection of proposal (Ford), reports on seminar, minutes of different meetings, 1978 - 1982) (Box 559)
- IEA Council meeting 1974, Scotland (Box 560)
- IEA Council meeting, Germany Sep 1975 (Box 561)
- Collection of un-sorted IEA documents and text, varies in years 1967-1972 (proposals, letters, correspondence etc', might be interesting) (Box 562)
- Publication: IEA, Phase II, stage 2, Science, December 1968 (pink cover, c/o UNESCO Hamburg) (Box 563)
- The USA and Cooperative International Education (1970) by Ralph Spence (TC) and Willis Griffin (U of Kentucky) (Box 564)
- Collection of documents 1970s, not sorted, [assuming from Husen] (Box 565)
- Dry Run, National Instruments: Hungary (Box 566)
- Report from the Netherlands (Box 566)
- IEA Newsletter since 1982: 1-15 (Box 567)
- IEA Stage II, National Reports (Box 568)
- IEA Tokyo meeting, Jan 1978 (Box 569)
- IEA Classroom Environment Study, report of activities 1979 - 1980, by Tamar Levin, TAU (Box 569)
- IEA Study of Reading Literacy (1992) (Box 570)
- Computer printouts of reports and statistics relating to comparative education in various countries and to methods of measurement of educational attainment, 1959-1992. Titles taken directly from the volume cover or first page. (Box 571-598)
  - Stage 2 School Univariates Working Copies (Box 571)
  - Item Analysis Population II Arskursvppd Sc21-29 Arkivex (Box 571)
  - Frequency: Determinants of earnings aggregates and all sectors (Box 571)
  - Population! Extra Science Analyses (Box 571)
  - Arkivex GH037-039 (Box 571)
  - Main Run- June 71 Student Univariates --Chile, Finland, France, New Zealand, Sweden, USA (Box 571)
  - Biavanates 3a. (Box 572)
  - Item and scale Analyses Population I/II and IV Arkivex (Box 572)
  - IEA Short Codebooks 75-08-29 R (Box 572)
  - Item Analyses (TSSA) Science AK 7,8,9 (Box 572)
  - Computer printouts of reports and statistics (Box 572)
  - Population B Math 4 Student Data (Box 572)
  - Weighted School Univariates Population II --Australia, Belgium, Chile, England, Federal Republic of Germany, Finland, Hungary, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 573)
  - NFER- G.C.E "O", "A" v. IEA Test Analysis (Box 573)
  - Stage 2 Population IV Student Bivariates Archive Copy First Batch of Countries First Run (155 Invariables)- Chile, England, Finland, France, New Zealand, Sweden, USA (Box 573)
  - School Univariates Teacher Weighted by Student Weights Population I, II, and IV Arkivex (Box 573)
  - Filbyggnad SWEA NF SWEA LF Inst. For International ped. (Box 573)
  - Mathematics Study Final Multiple Regression Analysis and sampling Plans as executed. (Box 573)
  - IEA Short Codebooks 75-08-29 D (Box 574)
  - Teacher Frequent Population I Weighted (Box 574)
  - Guts (Box 574)
  - SDPU Backup Material Case Listings From Copy Tapes (Box 574)
  - Population 4 (Box 574)
  - Mathematics Study Extra Copies Hypotheses 6 SPC A,B,C,D,E,F,G,H,I,J plus spares Hypotheses 01-54 (Box 575)
  - Stage 2 Population IV Student Univariates (additional variables) Archive Copy, First Batch of Countries Second Run (21x176 variables) - Chile, England, Fin. and, France, New Zealand, Sweden, USA (Box 575)
  - Teacher Univariates Population II Stockholm Unweighted (error ATFND) (Box 575)
  - GH 040 (Box 575)
  - Filbyggnad Lit-Projektet Population IV (Box 576)
  - MC002 11/7-75 Master Copy (Box 576)
  - Stage 2 Population IV between School Bivariates-- Australia, Belgium FL, Belgium FR, Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, France, Hungary, India, Iran, Israel, Italy, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, USA (Box 576)
  - M2004 11/7-75 Master Copy (Box 577)
  - BET Schools Weighted Population I, Science and Reading-- Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, Scotland, Sweden, USA (Box 577)
  - Mathematics Study N.F.E.R. English National Analysis Populations IIa and IIb IIIa and IIIb (Box 577)
  - Listening IEA File Sweden Stage 3 (Box 578)
  - Teacher Frequencies Population II Weighted-Australia, Belgium FL, Belgium FR, Chile, England, Finland, Fed. Rep. Germ., Hungary, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 578)
  - IEA Data Bank L Stage 2 SCH (s2000) (Box 578)
  - Student Univariates All Populations Sweden Arkivex (Box 578)
  - Computer printouts of reports and statistics (Box 578)
  - Math II Population B (Box 579)
  - Math II Population B Teacher and School Frequencies (Box 579)
  - IEA International Bivariates Univariates (Box 579)
  - Mathematics Study Bivariates Level 1,2,3,4,5 Univariates Level 1,2,3,4,5 June 65 Version (final) (Box 580)
  - Arkivex GH 033 (Box 580)
  - Filbyggnad Litteratur- Filer (Box 580)
  - Between Students Regressions (Weighted) Population II Science - Australia, Belgium (FL), Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, Hungary, India, Iran, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 581)
  - Stage 3 TCH (T3000) D (Box 581)
  - Stage 2 population II Student Bivariates Working Copy First Batch of Countries First Run (159 variables) -Australia Chile, England, FRG. Finland, Hungary, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA Second Batch of Countries (180 variables) Belgium FL, Belgium FR, India, Iran, Israel, Italy (Box 581)
  - Stage 2 Population IV Student Bivariates Working Copy First Batch of Countries First Run(155 Variables)-Chile, England, France, New Zealand, Sweden, USA (Box 582)
  - Stage 2 Population II Between School Correlation Working Copy-Australia, Belgium FL, Belgium FR, Chile, England, FRG, Finland, Hungary, India, Iran, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 582)
  - Scale Analysis for Finland Copy 1 (Box 582)
  - Opportunity to learn Math II Population A Allmon kurs (Box 583)
  - Mathematics Study International Bivariates and univariates Pan ultimate version (Box 583)
  - Mathematics Study un-weighted univariates Population Ia and Ib November 66 (Box 583)
  - Malmo Var Lists Population 1 Nom- Population 6 Nom Albert Feb- March 88 (Box 584)
  - Stage 3 English Sweden (Box 584)
  - Stage 2 population IV Student Bivariates (additional variables) Working Copy--First Batch 0f Countries Second Run (21x176 Variables) Chile England Finland France New Zealand Sweden USA (Box 584)
  - Teacher Univariates Population I Stockholm Data Processing Unit Unweighted (Error at End) (Box 584)
  - Student Univariates IEA Weights all grades ARIVEX (Box 584)
  - English Study Population IV (ME004) L (Box 585)
  - Between School Regressions Population II Weighted Reading Comprehension-Chile England Finland Hungary Israel Italy Netherlands New Zealand Scotland Sweden USA (Box 585)
  - Data bank Master Construction Copy (Box 585)
  - Computer printouts of reports and statistics (Box 585)
  - Q626H Population II. (Box 586)
  - French Student Numbers and Strategies Weighted (Box 586)
  - Kenya FIL Reliability, Correlations, Factor Analysis (Box 586)
  - Student General Questionnaire Univariates Civics Between Studies Weighted Part 1 of 6 (Box 586)
  - Age x Grade, Teacher x Subject (Box 586)
  - DEFF Between School (Box 587)
  - Stage 2 School Univariates All Populations and Countries Archive Copy (Box 587)
  - Mathematics Study (illegible label) (Box 587)
  - T2000 7/8- 75 Master Copy (Box 587)
  - Item Analysis Populations II ARSKURSVPPDELAD WKRC21 Arkivex (Box 587)
  - Botswana Bivariates Population II Govern Teacher Variables (Box 588)
  - Stage II Population II between School File--Australia, Belgium FL, Belgium FR, Chile, England, Fed. Rep Germ., Finland, Hungary, India, Iran, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 588)
  - Larar Univariater Univ31 Univ32 Univ33 SKOL Univariate Univ34 Population III Arkivex (Box 589)
  - Main Run Student Bivariates Master File July 1971 (Box 589)
  - Between Schools weighted population IV Science Reading Literature-Australia, Belgium FR, Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, France, Hungary, Israel, Italy, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, USA (Box 589)
  - Stage 2 Population I Student Bivariates-Belgium FL Belgium FR Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, Hungary, India, Iran, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, Thailand, USA (Box 590)
  - Stage 2 Population II between School Bivariates-Australia, Belgium FL, Belgium FR, Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, Hungary, India, Iran, Israel, Italy, Japan, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 590)
  - Weighted School Univariates Population IV-- Australia, Belgium FL, Belgium FR, Chile, England, Fed. Rep. Germ., Finland, France, Hungary, Israel, Italy, Netherlands, New Zealand, Scotland, Sweden, Thailand, USA (Box 590)
  - Stage 2 Deffs Means, regressions, and Experimental Runs (Box 590)
  - PUB (L. Mahlek) June 1979 Whole sample and science and technical tracks 90D-902,942 (Box 591)
  - Stage 3 English and French Writing and Speaking Weighting Exercise Also: Reliability (Box 591)
  - Regressions Coetot and Antila Weighted Population II Civics Between Studies-Italy Netherlands, New Zealand, USA (with Newton and Spurrel Rerun for New Zealand) (Box 591)
  - Arkivex GH 035 (Box 591)
  - Computer printouts of reports and statistics (Box 591)
  - Botswana Bivariates Population II School variables (Box 592)
  - M2002 SMIDA Ingrid Mattson (Box 592)
  - Factor Analyses of Instruments K,H, & R Populations II & IV-Chile, England, Finland, Sweden (missing factor analyses) (Box 592)
  - English Regression II Extra (Box 593)
  - Botswana Bivariates Population I-III, Student variables (Box 593)
  - December 10-Documentation (Print Doc:) (Box 594)
  - Botswana Bivariates Population II Private, Teacher variables (Box 594)
  - Stage 2 Teacher Univariates from New York Data Processing Unit Working Copy (Box 594)
  - Botswana Univariates tests (Box 595)
  - Analysis Steps from Stage 2 1971-1972 (Box 595)
  - MC004 26/6 -75 Master Copy (Box 595)
  - Botswana School Univariates (Box 595)
  - Literature Population II BET School Regressions (un-weighted) Stockholm File Copy-Chile, England, Finland, Italy, New Zealand, Sweden, USA (Box 596)
  - English Univariates Students Weighted (Box 596)
  - Regressions Total Discussions Civics Weighted Between studies-Germany, Finland, Ireland, Italy, Netherlands, New Zealand, USA (Israel and Iran not done) (Box 596)
  - Specialist Science Instructions by Test Cross Tabs (Box 596)
  - Botswana Univariates Teachers variables (Box 597)
  - School Univariates all Populations all Countries Weighted in between schools (Box 597)
  - World Bank Study Thailand Population II (Box 597)
  - Math II Population A Student Analysis (Box 598)
  - Math I Populations 3A (Box 598)
  - Ingrid Lisrel-Kurs (Box 598)